Some men dream of conquering the world. Roger Corman created his own.
Corman's World is a documentary film directed by Alex Stapleton.
A chronicle of the long career of American filmmaker Roger Corman, the most tenacious and ingenious low-budget producer
and director in the US film industry, a pioneer of independent filmmaking and discoverer of new talent.
Self - Filmmaker, played by Roger Corman.
Self - Makeup Designer, played by Gary J. Tunnicliffe.
Self - Screenwriter, played by Frances Doel.
Self - Corman's Wife - Producer, played by Julie Corman.
Self - Actor, played by David Carradine.
Self - Filmmaker, played by John Sayles.
Roger William Corman (April 5, 1926 – May 9, 2024) was an
American film director, producer, and actor.
Known under various monikers such as "The Pope of Pop Cinema", "The Spiritual Godfather of the New
Hollywood", and "The King of Cult", he was known as a trailblazer in the world of independent film.
Many of the more than 500 features directed or produced by Corman were low-budget films that later attracted a cult following, such as A Bucket of Blood (1959), The Little
Shop of Horrors (1960), The Intruder (1962), X: The Man with the X-ray Eyes (1963), and the counterculture films The Wild Angels (1966) and The Trip (1967).
House of Usher (1960) became the first of eight films directed by Corman that were adapted from the
tales of Edgar Allan Poe, and which collectively came to be known as the "Poe Cycle".
In 1964, Corman became the youngest filmmaker to have a retrospective at the Cinémathèque
française, as well as in the British Film Institute and the Museum of Modern Art.
He was the co-founder of New World Pictures, the founder of New Concorde and was a
longtime member of the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences.
In 2009, he was awarded an Academy Honorary Award "for his
rich engendering of films and filmmakers".
Corman was also famous for handling the American distribution of many films by noted foreign directors, including
Federico Fellini (Italy), Ingmar Bergman (Sweden), François Truffaut (France) and Akira Kurosawa (Japan).
He mentored and gave a start to many young film directors such as Francis Ford Coppola, Ron Howard, Martin Scorsese, Jonathan Demme, Peter Bogdanovich,
Joe Dante, John Sayles, and James Cameron, and was highly influential in the New Hollywood filmmaking movement of the 1960s and 1970s.
He also helped to launch the careers of actors including Peter Fonda, Jack
Nicholson, Dennis Hopper, Bruce Dern, Diane Ladd, and William Shatner.
Corman occasionally acted in films by directors who started with him, including The Godfather Part II (1974), The
Silence of the Lambs (1991), Philadelphia (1993), Apollo 13 (1995), and The Manchurian Candidate (2004).
A documentary about Corman's life and career titled Corman's World: Exploits of a Hollywood Rebel,
directed by Alex Stapleton, premiered at the Sundance and Cannes Film Festivals in 2011.
The film's TV rights were picked up by A&E IndieFilms
after a well-received screening at Sundance.
The film explores themes of cinema on cinema, movie
business, 1970s, biography, woman director.